JEREMY SMITH

Junior Developer

📞 07398 722784 @ jeremyrrsmith@gmail.com % https://github.com/JRRS1982/Portfolio



PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am an Agile software developer with 5 years experience in financial advice (private client wealth management) and 10 years experience in property management, valuation and development.

I first started learning to coding 18 years ago as a gaming geek and have always kept an interest in technology. The first half of my professional career was spent solving problems and managing contracts in property and finance.

I have now come full circle to follow my passion for technology. I left a prestigious investment bank where I was well regarded to join Makers Academy and become a developer.

I like the efficences that software development grants to companies, allowing better use of time and better products to be created. I enjoy working as part of a team, pushing to the collective repository and resolving any conflicts.

CODING PROJECTS

Acebook: A Facebook Clone

A group project collaboratively working to create a clone of Facebook.

- Deployed here: https://acebook-business-logic.herokuapp.com/
- Daily stand-ups, retros, working with a kanban board to manage tasks in an agile manner, TDD'ing branches to merge to master after peer review.
- https://github.com/JRRS1982/acebook-business-logic

Boris Bikes: A Ruby program

A simple project used to train good development attributes.

- · An encapsulated, test driven, object oriented Ruby program.
- Tidy code, with good test coverage, nice commit messages and hopefully and demonstration of good practice.
- % https://github.com/JRRS1982/Boris-Bike/tree/master/Boris_Bikes

Bank Tech Test

A typical tech test: I have used here to demonstrate best practice

- This used test driven development with mocking, objects, refactoring, and modelling all on Github with fairly tidy commit messages.
- https://github.com/JRRS1982/Bank_Tech_Test

Codewars: Various Problems Solved

A repo containing problem sets I have conquered at Codewars

- I have used this site to practice different skills, this repo currently contains six solutions to those problem sets.
- % https://github.com/JRRS1982/Codewars

SKILLS

Ruby	Rails	RSpec	HTML	CSS
TDD	ООР	Git	GitHub	Trello
JIRA	Heroku	Post	greSQL	Scrums
Sprints Bootstrap Capybara				
Jasmine Sinatra Javascript				
Communication Leadership				
Various CRM platforms Travis Node				
Team Management Problem Solving				
Organisation Business improvement				

EDUCATION

Software Development Bootcamp

Makers Academy

1 02/2019 - 05/2019

- Intensive coding bootcamp.
- Front and backend software development / web development.

Post Grad Diploma Real Estate

University of Kingston

1 09/2007 - 07/2009

- A part time distance course completed while in full time education.
- Corporate Strategy, Investment and Development Appraisal, Information Technology, Securitisation, and the Regulatory Environment, Real Estate Valuation, Asset Management, Economic Sustainability and an International Project.

Business Admin. B.A. (hons)

Plymouth University

1 09/2002 - 07/2005

 Business Analysis, Business Management, Human Resource Management, Economics, Financial and Business Accounting, Business Finance, Marketing Planning, Employment Law, Business Law and Information Technology.

TRAINING / COURSES

Bowling (scorecard) challenge

A repo containing my solution to the common bowling scorecard kata.

 This used test driven development with mocking, objects, refactoring, and modelling all on Github with fairly tidy commit messages.

https://github.com/JRRS1982/bowling-challenge

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wealth Management Assistant

Close Brothers Asset Management

1 07/2017 - 01/2019

♀ Liverpool Street, London.

Providing support to private clients by advising them what to invest in and how to better manage their money by doing it for them.

- The London representative on the company 'business improvement forum'.
- I was specifically selected for / by No1 advisor in the company.

Sales Consultant

AMPP Group

1 04/2017 - 07/2017

With UK and Indian governmental support and partnership, I contacted C-Suite management in global multinational companies and objection handled gatekeepers to book appointments between the CEO and my director.

• I made connections, but no calls converted into sales and I did not enjoy the 'hotbox sales' culture therefore decided to leave.

Wealth Management Assistant

Thomas Miller Wealth Management

1 03/2016 - 04/2017

♀ City, London

A fantastic and friendly wealth management / investment department that provided advice to private clients.

- · I assisted in the development of a new CRM system.
- I solved multiple administrative issues with clients and Investment team reporting.

Client Service Executive

Foster Denovo

1 05/2014 - 03/2016

♥ City, London

A financial advice company

While here I restructured their client management spreadsheets, which led to them cutting a number of unprofitable clients, discovering plans that they were not charging for and providing easier management. This system was then used across the team.

Team Leader (Initial Market Report Team)

Countrywide Corporate 🛗 08/2010 - 03/2014

08/2010 - 03/2014 **♥** Weybridge, Surrey

A property repossession and then sales company.

- I managed the team through it's relocation from Weybridge to Bracknell, during my time at the helm of this team of 10 we had the lowest turnover in the company.
- I started as a property valuation administrator here and was promoted into the lead role after demonstrating my work ethic.

Freecode Camp - responsive web design (300hr course)

Udemy - Comprehensive Ruby Programming

Sololearn - Ruby pathway

Many 'meetups' on various subjects.

Bit part in side projects such as assisting a friend set up a mobile based AI financial advice company with voice recognition.

PASSIONS

Cooking for friends

É

Useful software



Task management software



Countryside trips



Cycling / Camping / Wild Swimming



Altruism



Reading